PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(metal clattering)
（金属咔嗒声）
- You've just seen how any color
- 你已经了解到了
can be represented by blending together
混合红绿蓝三色
different amounts of three colors,
可以代表
red, green and blue.
多少种颜色
For example, the RGB value of this gold color
举个例子 这种金色的 RGB 值包含
is 100% red, slightly less green,
100% 的红色，稍微少一点的绿色
and no blue,
不含有一丁点蓝色
but as you may have noticed in the previous exercise,
但你从前面的练习中 可能也意识到了
it's fairly difficult to find the correct RGB values
很难为需要的颜色找到
to match a desired color.
匹配的 RGB 值
So artists have developed new ways
所以艺术家们研发了一种新的
to specify colors in a more intuitive way.
更直观的确定颜色的方式
One popular method they use is called HSL,
一种流行的方式被称为 HSL
short for hue, saturation, and lightness,
分别为色相、饱和度以及亮度
similar to the HSV we saw earlier.
和我们前面看到的 HSV 相似
Artists use a tool called a color wheel
艺术家们用被称为色轮的东西
to pick the hue and saturation they like.
选取他们喜欢的色相和饱和度
Hue is what we normally call color,
色相就是我们通常说的颜色
is based on the position around this wheel,
它基于绕色轮的方向
such as this red.
比如说这种红色
Saturation defines how pure a color is,
饱和度定义了颜色有多纯
and saturation is based on the distance
饱和度基于到色轮圆心的
from the center of this wheel.
距离来决定
If we want to desaturate,
如果我们想去色
we move inward,
就向中心移动
and if we want to saturate,
如果我们想添色
we move outward.
就向外围移动
For example, to saturate this shade of red,
举个例子 让这种红色变浓
we remove any contribution of green and blue,
我们移除任何绿色和蓝色做的贡献
whereas to desaturate it,
反之 若要让红色变淡
we instead increase the contribution
我们则提高
of green and blue.
绿色和蓝色的贡献
Taken to the extreme, this trends towards grey
当到达极端情况时 它就变成了灰色
because the three color contributions are equal.
因为三种颜色的贡献是相等的
So at full desaturation,
所以，完全去色之后
our red becomes achromatic, or colorless.
红色变成了消色差的 或称为无色的
If an artist wants to use a strong yellow,
如果艺术家想用强烈的黄色
they first have to find the yellow hue they want.
他们首先找到他们需要的黄色的色相
Then they move in the radial direction
然后他们在径向的方向移动
to saturate or desaturate it.
来添色和去色
Finally, there is lightness,
最后 是亮度
which is adjusted using a separate slider.
它用一个独立的滑动条来控制
For example, we can take our yellow
举个例子 我们可以让我们的黄色
from very low lightness like this
从一个非常低的亮度 像这样
to a very high lightness like this.
变成非常高的亮度 像这样
You can already see that this is a much more
你已经发现 相比于 RGB 值
intuitive way of finding colors
这是寻找颜色
compared to using RGB values.
更加直观的方法了
Okay, let's pause here
好啦 让我们暂停一下
so you can get the hang of HSL color selection
这样你就可以在下个练习中
in the next exercise. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
上手 HSL 颜色选法了 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox